<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>com.redis.RedisInsight</id>

    <name>Redis Insight</name>
    <summary>Developer GUI for Redis, by Redis</summary>

    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>SSPL-1.0</project_license>
    <developer_name>Redis, Inc</developer_name>

    <categories>
        <category>Development</category>
    </categories>

    <description>
        <p>RedisInsight is an intuitive and efficient GUI for Redis, allowing you to interact with
            your databases and manage your data—with built-in support for Redis modules.</p>
        <p>
            RedisInsight Highlights:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>Browse, filter, visualise your key-value Redis data structures and see key values in
                different formats (including JSON, Hex, ASCII, etc.)</li>
            <li>CRUD support for lists, hashes, strings, sets, sorted sets, and streams</li>
            <li>CRUD support for [JSON](https://redis.io/json/) data structure</li>
            <li>Interactive tutorials to learn easily, among other things, how to leverage the native JSON data structure 
                supporting structured querying and full-text search, including vector similarity search for your AI use cases</li>
            <li>Contextualised recommendations to optimize performance and memory usage. The list of recommendations gets updated 
                as you interact with your database</li>
            <li>Profiler - analyze every command sent to Redis in real-time</li>
            <li>SlowLog - analyze slow operations in Redis instances based on the Slowlog command</li>
            <li>Pub/Sub - support for Redis pub/sub, enabling subscription to channels and posting
                messages to channels</li>
            <li>Bulk actions - Delete the keys in bulk based on the filters set in Browser or Tree
                view</li>
            <li>Workbench - advanced command line interface with intelligent command
                auto-complete, complex data visualizations and support for the raw mode</li>
            <li>Command auto-complete support for [search and query](https://redis.io/search/) capability, [JSON](https://redis.io/json/) and 
                [time series](https://redis.io/timeseries/) data structures</li>
            <li>Visualizations of your [search and query](https://redis.io/search/) indexes and results</li>
            <li>Ability to build your own data visualization plugins</li>
            <li>Built-in click-through guides for Redis capabilities</li>
            <li>Officially supported for Redis OSS, [Redis Cloud](https://redis.io/cloud/). Works with Microsoft Azure Cache for Redis</li>
        </ul>
    </description>

    <url type="homepage">https://redis.com/redis-enterprise/redis-insight/</url>
    <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/RedisInsight/RedisInsight</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/RedisInsight/RedisInsight/issues</url>

    <launchable type="desktop-id">com.redis.RedisInsight.desktop</launchable>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>
                https://github.com/flathub/com.redis.RedisInsight/raw/master/flathub/main_screen.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>
                https://github.com/flathub/com.redis.RedisInsight/raw/master/flathub/tree_view.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>
                https://github.com/flathub/com.redis.RedisInsight/raw/master/flathub/wb1.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>
                https://github.com/flathub/com.redis.RedisInsight/raw/master/flathub/wb2.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>
                https://github.com/flathub/com.redis.RedisInsight/raw/master/flathub/analysis.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>
                https://github.com/flathub/com.redis.RedisInsight/raw/master/flathub/tips.png</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>

    <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

    <releases>
        <release version="2.58.0.124102" date="2024-10-01">
            <description></description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.56.0.122216" date="2024-09-09">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Hide or show TTL for individual hash fields to create a cleaner, more efficient workspace.</li>
                    <li>Enhanced vector data representation with updated 32-bit and 64-bit vector formatters in the Browser.</li>
                    <li>UX optimizations to make it easier and more intuitive to connect to your Redis Data Integration (RDI) instance within Redis Insight.</li>
                    <li>A new timestamp formatter in the Browser to improve data readability. This formatter converts timestamps in hash fields to a human-readable format, making it easier to interpret results, validate and optimize queries, and inspect indexed data when using the search and query capability.</li>
                    <li>Date and time format customization to make the data more intuitive in Redis Insight. This flexibility helps match your local time zone or standardize it to UTC for better alignment in time-critical operations across global teams.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.54.0.119100" date="2024-08-06">
            <description>
                <p>Release notes</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Redis Insight now comes with the support for Redis Data Integration (RDI) - a powerful tool designed to seamlessly synchronize data from your existing database to Redis in near real-time. RDI establishes a data streaming pipeline that mirrors data from your existing database to Redis Software, so if a record is added or updated, those changes automatically flow into Redis. This no-code solution enables seamless data integration and faster data access so you can build real-time apps at any scale. Use RDI version 1.2.7 or later to seamlessly create, validate, deploy, and monitor your data pipelines within Redis Insight. To get started, switch to the "Redis Data Integration" tab on the page with the list of Redis databases and add your RDI endpoint to Redis Insight. </li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.52.0.116527" date="2024-06-28">
            <description>
             <p>Release notes</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Redis Insight now supports setting expiration for individual hash fields through intuitive Browser controls. The hash field expiration is a highly requested feature available in the first release candidate of Redis 7.4.</li>
                    <li>Redis, with its high performance and versatile data structures, is an excellent choice for implementing Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). Our new built-in tutorial provides an overview of how Redis can be leveraged in a RAG use case. To get started, open the "Insights" panel in the top right corner and try the new tutorial.</li>
                    <li>UX optimizations for displaying the values of keys in the Browser. The new layout includes controls for editing key values that appear only when you hover over them, optimizing the use of space and providing a cleaner interface.</li>
                    <li>Support for applying the JSON formatting in Browser for values of keys with float numbers that contain 10 or more decimal places.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.50.0.113335" date="2024-05-30">
         <description>
          <p>Release notes</p>
              <ul>
                  <li>New tutorial exploring several common Redis use cases with paired-up sample data that will get you started quicker with your empty database.</li>
                  <li>UX enhancements for the JSON data structure in the Browser to prevent collapsing the entire structure when updating a JSON value. Includes performance optimizations for loading JSON documents containing numerous objects.</li>
                  <li>Added a quick access button to sign in to your Redis Cloud account from anywhere within Redis Insight, to import existing databases or create a new account with a free database. Integration with your Redis Cloud account is currently available only in the desktop Redis Insight version.</li>
                  <li>Changed the sorting order in the Tree view to lexicographical.</li>
              </ul>
         </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.48.0.109205" date="2024-04-11"/>
        <release version="2.46.0.107453" date="2024-03-28"/>
        <release version="2.44.0.105394" date="2024-02-29"/>
        <release version="2.42.0.103316" date="2024-01-31"/>
        <release version="2.40.0.100659" date="2023-12-27"/>
        <release version="2.38.0" date="2023-11-30"/>
        <release version="2.36.0.95755" date="2023-10-27"/>
        <release version="2.34.0.93425" date="2023-09-28"/>
        <release version="2.32.0.91313" date="2023-08-31"/>
        <release version="2.30.0.87615" date="2023-07-27"/>
        <release version="2.28.0.85123" date="2023-06-29"/>
        <release version="2.26.0.82224" date="2023-05-31"/>
        <release version="2.24.0.79637" date="2023-04-28"/>
        <release version="2.22.1.77460" date="2023-03-30"/>
        <release version="2.22.0.77328" date="2023-03-30"/>
        <release version="2.20.0.75358" date="2023-03-01"/>
        <release version="2.18.0.72915" date="2023-01-31"/>
        <release version="2.16.0.70401" date="2022-12-28"/>
        <release version="2.14.0" date="2022-11-30"/>
    </releases>
</component>
